Before we embark on the final exercise,
what I do want to go ahead and show you is
that we've built all this stuff.
And then so in case anyone hasn't had the chance to use it,
I'm going to show you how to deploy your app
because after all once you've built something,
it'd be nice to actually deploy it and share it with people.
So let's go ahead and do that right now
and I'll show you how to do that with NetLify.
So none of this has any code.
So basically NetLify is a deployment service somewhere
to I think Versel, AWS CloudFair.
There's a bunch of them out there.
I just happened to be showing you NetLify.
And so basically with the free account
what all that we need to do here is we just add any site.
So I can import it from any project from GitHub directly
and we'll see why this is important in just a moment.
So basically authorizes it with my GitHub credentials.
And then we just did the TypeScript, let's see,
TypeScript, search search, maybe I do that.
And there you go, TypeScript and ViewWorkshop.
And so what we'll do is it'll detect a few things
as far as the owner, branch it to deploy.
And so currently for me, normally your app
is going to be in your root directory.
But for me, it's currently an app.
And then the build command is going to be NPM run built.
And then after that, all I do is hit deploy site.
And so what's really cool, I think
about deployment these days, if anyone's done any old school
deployment, is that a lot of things
have been automated for you.
So because we've hooked it up directly to our GitHub repo,
we get a lot of basically benefits out of this.
And so even just for the free projects of,
it's pretty incredible.
So you can see here that we have an isolated container
that's currently going to go ahead and building all the things
and it's deploying it.
And what's great is that once you're done with this,
you can see that, OK, well, I can still show you
some things while this thing is broken.
But because it's actually hooked up to your GitHub repo,
what it does, it means that it auto-tracks and deployments.
So in the instance, for example, let's say that we
wanted to update our tagline.
So if I go to the nav bar, for example,
and inside the tagline, that's currently being imported on that.
So I say tagline, it looks like it got deleted at some point.
So track whatever you want to eat.
And then, if I just commit this, oh, I know why it's broken.
OK, it's fine.
Get commit to do, to do, to do, to do, to do.
So feature a tagline, let me check out, I forgot.
It's watching the main branch.
So we're all the way up and like 11.
So just to show you that this works real quick,
inside of my app.view, we can go ahead and just add
like an H1 to say hello.
So I'm going to delete this commit later.
So get commit, title, delete, me, later, get push.
OK, so one thing that it does for you by default
is that because it's watching your main branch,
you notice that it automatically picks up that change
and then automatically deploy it.
And what's really nice about the deployment services
these days, especially for those getting started with new projects,
is that it, particularly with NetLify,
all of your deploy are atomic.
In other words, they live independently of one another.
So in the event you ever need to roll back,
it really is as simple as basically clicking on the deploy
that you want, and basically saying, hey, let's go ahead
and lock it to this particular branch.
And this is huge when it comes to deployment efforts,
because you can iterate a lot faster and more importantly,
you don't have to worry that rollbacks
are going to be really expensive in case something breaks.
But otherwise, just notice that if you're using building any apps,
check out these deployment services,
so they can do a lot for your workflow.
And when they deploy everything, they all have their own CDN
and all that caching and stuff taken care of,
which, as those of you who've done that in the past,
no, it's really painful to manage that on your own.
So that's basically my little pitch just to something
to keep in mind when you're trying to deploy your next project.
And so a lot of them have really generous tiers
free tiers in that kind of stuff.
So be sure to check it out.
And that's not even to talk about serverless functions,
which is the whole thing of itself, so that,
but I did manage to deploy working.
So I thought I might show you what happened,
and then that way you can learn from my mistake.
So we check out the build and deploy configuration,
basically, for how it is being built.
Prior to this, actually, this is what it looks like.
So let me just delete this real quick and save.
So typically, when you're deploying your app
and it's on the root directory,
it will automatically fetch some configuration,
like automatically detect that you need to deploy
the disk folder, all that fun stuff.
Well, what you might have noticed is,
if you're looking at my builds right now,
it knows that my base directory is app,
because that's what I configured.
But I forgot to tell it that the published directory
is gonna be the disk folder within the app.
And so basically, once I came in here
and then dropped in the disk folder,
that's what made everything work, which is why here,
now when I click on the deploy, you'll see,
hey, look, everything works now, we have our restaurants,
we have our dishes, this is great.
And then now that we have that working,
something that's fun that you might want to know about,
is that this randomly generated hash here,
you can actually customize that.
So for me, I'm just gonna go ahead,
and this would be the two-eat NVC app.
And so if I save that, you'll see that within a matter of seconds,
it's already been swapped out as a subdomain
since it's available.
And you can see it actually does work,
and now that can be shared, it's like the promo link
for the app, which is actually pretty cool.
When you think about the fact that we spend
on the time building and creating things,
I mean, we wanna need to share it, right,
to share it with the world so people can use it
and do things with it.